Guide to the Civil War Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Civil War manuscripts, 1861-1902; Series II
  - Lincoln's Cabinet-engravings
    - Speed, James (1812-1887). Engraving by Max Rosenthal, 1892. Signed "James Speed" in the plate. 2 copies. 1 unmounted. 1 inlaid and signed in pencil by the artist. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Stanton, Edwin McMasters (1814-1869). Engraving by A.H. Ritchie. Signed "Edwin M. Stanton" in the plate. Inlaid. 2 copies. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Usher, John Palmer (1816-1889). Engraving signed in the plate. Inlaid. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Welles, Gideon (1802-1878). Engraving showing Welles seated at a table. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Welles, Gideon (1802-1878). Engraving of Welles' head, signed in the plate. Engraved by J.M. Butler. Inlaid. (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Waters, 2nd Lieutenant Albertus Aretius, De Kalb Tigers, Company A., 100th Regiment, Indiana Volunteers, copy of diary, 1862 August 20-1863 July 10 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Weir, James E., letters to parents, 1861- 1865 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Willard, Lovell F., diary, 1863 April-December 20 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    Lovell F. Willard was born October 6, 1832, at Wardsboro, Vermont. His father was Eli Willard, born at Wardsboro, Vermont, October 2, 1783, and died August 3, 1864. His mother was Lucy Frost who was born November 17, 1787, and died August 24, 1846. Eli and Lucy were married at Townshend, Vermont, January 31, 1810.
    Lovell Willard married Jane Deborah White Hobart on July 12, 1854. She was born March 30, 1834. Lovell died January 10, 1864, at Horican, Wisconsin, after contracting smallpox from a vaccination. They had five children. Lucy Augusta, born May 2, 1855, died March 13, 1935; Henrietta Lydia (or Lydiann), born November 7, 1856, died November 11, 1942; Jane Deborah, born March 28, 1859, died January 14, 1893; Sylvia Elizabeth, born July 12, 1861, died June 14, 1885; Lovella Flora, born May 9, 1863, died May 16, 1938.
    Lucy married James Clifton Hall (January 21, 1851-April 17, 1906) on April 30, 1874. They had five children. The youngest was Hattie Marie born October 5, 1887, in Cherokee, Iowa. She died September 24, 1950, at Salem, South Dakota. She married Alexander Boyd Knox II January 3, 1912. They had four children. Alexander Boyd born April 6, 1913; Cather(ine) Jean born November 15, 1916, died November 25, 1978; Harriet Marie, born July 28, 1919; and Mary Alice born October 30, 1920. She, Mary Alice Albertson, is the donor of the diary of 1st Lieutenant Lovell F. Willard who served with Company "C" of the 29th Regiment of Wisconsin volunteers.
  - Woodman, Horatio, discharge paper of John Hall, 1866 December 31 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Young, W. H., letter, 1863 November 18 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter and blank forms, 1864-1865, undated (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Oversize
    - Barnes, Paul, printed sheet music, "Good-bye Dolly Gray," music by Paul Barnes, words by Will D. Cobb, 1902 (Box 31A)
    - Gile, David Herrick, 2 flags, Union Jack, silk; United States flag, 37 stars, silk (1867?) (Box 31A)
    - Norman, William F., autograph letter signed to his wife Louise, 1862 (Box 31A)
    - Broadside, "Conditions of Peace Required of the So-called Seceded States," New York, 1861 April 24 (Box 31A)
    - Newspaper: Boston Evening Transcript, 1862 June 3 (Box 31A)
    - Newspaper: Evening Post, 1862 September 12 (Box 31A)
    - Newspaper: New York Herald, 1864 August 19 (Box 31A)
    - Newspaper: New York Herald (4 copies), 1865 April 15 (Box 31A)
    - Newspaper: Boston Daily Journal, 1865 April 15 (Box 31A)
    - Newspaper: New York Herald, 1865 April 16-18 (Box 31A)